Preliminary Guide to the Yale School of Drama Production Casebook Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Yale School of Drama Production Casebook Collection
1966-2001
DRA 13
Yale University Arts Library
4.59
(11 boxes)
Collection contains dramaturg protocols and production research related to Yale School of Drama plays, submitted in partial fulfillment of dramaturgical coursework.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale School of Drama Production Casebook Collection was housed in the former Drama Library until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains dramaturg protocols and production research related to Yale School of Drama plays, submitted in partial fulfillment of dramaturgical coursework.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Drama -- Technique; Drama; Opera -- Dramaturgy
- Box listing
  - Volpone, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Are You Now or Have You Ever Been, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - The Father, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Bingo, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Don Juan, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Dynamite Tonite, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - General Gorgeous, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Walk the Dog, Willie, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Durango Flash, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - White Marriage, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Julius Caesar, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Suicide in Bflat, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Ivanov, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Puntila, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Man is Man, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - The Wild Duck, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Tales From the Vienna Woods, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - The Seagull, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Mistaken Identities, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Mahagonny, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - The Bundle, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Reunion, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Terra Nova, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Wings, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Ghost Sonata, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Bartholemew Fair, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Death Comes to Us All, Mary Agnes, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Farmyard, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - The Duchess of Malfi, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - The Family Reunion, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Festival of New Plays, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Narrow Road to the Deep North, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - The Three Sisters, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - The Visit, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Earth Spirit, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Alcestis, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Euripides at Bay, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Mad Dog Blues, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Jack, or the Submission, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Returning and Interludes, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Lear Dream, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Fanshen, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - House of York, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - The Philanderer, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Lower Depths, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - La Ronde, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Pillars of Society, 1982-1983 (2) (Box 3)
  - Phaedra, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - A Touch of the Poet, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Hello and Goodbye, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - A Doll House, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - The Hostage, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Richard II, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - A Moon for the Misbegotten, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Countess Cathleen, 1983-984 (Box 3)
  - The Broken Pitcher, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - The Vultures, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Pericles, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - The Three Sisters, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - The Misanthrope, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Fences, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - A Play of Giants, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Henry IV, Part I, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Pacific Overtures, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - L'Aiglon, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Coriolanus, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Tartuffe, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Talley's Folly, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - The Bathhouse, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Platonov, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Lorenzaccio, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Samson Agonistes, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Lydie Breeze, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - The Prince of Homburg, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Little Eeyolf, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Othello, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Watertown Primary, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - The Suicide, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Marriage, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Heartbreak House, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Translations, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - A Walk in the Woods, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Everything in the Garden, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - A Place with the Pigs, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - True Blue and Trembling, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - The Alchemist, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Four Saints in Three Acts, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Elizabeth, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - The Dragon, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Neapolitan Ghosts, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - A Winter's Tale, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - The Piano Lesson, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - The Miser, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Long Day's Journey Into Night, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Ah, Wilderness!, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - The Alchemist, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Kiss of the Spiderwoman, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - As You Like It, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - King John, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Moon Over Miami, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Cobb, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Summerfolk, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Playboy of the West Indies, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Ste. Carmen of the Main, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Pericles, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Two Trains Running, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Miss Julie, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Pygmalion, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Troilus and Cressida, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Summer and Smoke, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Hamlet, Prince of California, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - The Fly, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - The Convert, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Fathers and Sons, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - The Tempest, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Scapin, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Underground, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Ivanov, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - A Moon for the Misbegotten, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Search and Destroy, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Largo Desolato, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Hamlet, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Twelfth Night, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Woyzeck, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Tom's Suite, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Othello, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - The Name of Oedipus, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Edward II, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Struggles of the Dogs and the Black, undated (Box 7)
  - The Pelican, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Don Juan, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - The Seagull, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Hamlet, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - The Colored Museum, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Children of Paradise, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Free Ascent, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - The Witching of Drexel Weems, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Peer Gynt, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - School for Wives, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - The Architect and the Emperor of Assyria, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Suddenly Last Summer, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - The Pelican, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - School for Wives, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Oleanna, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Mump and Smoot, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - The Green Bird, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Saint Joan of the Stockyards, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Ruffian on the Stair, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Orpheus Descending, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Fences, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Le Bourgeois Avant-Garde, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Waiting for Godot, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Macbeth, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Dreissena Polymorpha: The Zebra Mussels, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Teacup for a Shallow Apocalypse, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - The Oriki of a Grasshopper, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - The Lady and the Sea, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Danton's Death, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Through the Leaves, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - The Wedding Dress, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Pentecost, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Landscape of the Body, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - The Beaux' Stratagem, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Tartuffe, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Henry IV, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - The Cryptogram, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - The Adventures of Amy Bock, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - Candida, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Petersburg, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - The Collection, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - January 24th, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Farmyard /Ghost Train, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - The Collection, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Measure for Measure, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Peter and Wendy, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Hayfever, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - The Curse of the Starving Class, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Richard III, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - The Imaginary Invalid, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Betrayal, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Prince of Homburg, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Rice Boy, 2000-2001 (Box 11)